

 

import 'question.dart';

const List<Question> questions = [
  Question(
    question:
        '1. Who is the current captain of the Bangladesh national cricket team?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Tamim Iqbal',
      'b) Mushfiqur Rahim',
      'c) Shakib Al Hasan',
      'd) Mahmudullah Riyad'
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '2. Who is the highest run-scorer in T20 Internationals for Bangladesh?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Tamim Iqbal',
      'b) Mushfiqur Rahim',
      'c) Shakib Al Hasan',
      'd) Mahmudullah Riyad'
    ],
  ), 
  Question(
    question: '3. In what continent is Brazil located?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Europe',
      'b) Asia',
      'c) North America',
      'd) South America',
    ],
  ),
 
  Question(
    question:
        '4. Who is the only Bangladeshi bowler to take a Test match hat-trick?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Mashrafe Mortaza',
      'b) Taijul Islam',
      'c) Rubel Hossain',
      'd) Shakib Al Hasan'
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '5. Which stadium in Dhaka is known as the "Home of Cricket" in Bangladesh?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Sher-e-Bangla National Cricket Stadium',
      'b) Sylhet International Cricket Stadium',
      'c) Mirpur Stadium',
      'd) Zahur Ahmed Chowdhury Stadium'
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '6. Who is the first Bangladeshi cricketer to score a century in Test cricket?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Mohammad Ashraful',
      'b) Tamim Iqbal',
      'c) Mushfiqur Rahim',
      'd) Shakib Al Hasan'
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '7. Which bowler from Bangladesh is known for his nickname "Fizz"?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Mashrafe Mortaza',
      'b) Mustafizur Rahman',
      'c) Rubel Hossain',
      'd) Taskin Ahmed'
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '8. What is the capital of France?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Madrid',
      'b) Paris',
      'c) Berlin',
      'd) Rome',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '9. What is the name of the domestic T20 cricket tournament in Bangladesh?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Bangladesh Premier League (BPL)',
      'b) Dhaka Premier League (DPL)',
      'c) Bangladesh Super League (BSL)',
      'd) Bangladesh T20 Challenge'
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '10. Who is the only Bangladeshi cricketer to score a double century in Test cricket?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Tamim Iqbal',
      'b) Mushfiqur Rahim',
      'c) Shakib Al Hasan',
      'd) Mahmudullah Riyad'
    ],
  ),
  // Question(
  //   question:
  //       '11. Who was the coach of the Bangladesh national cricket team during their historic victory over England in the 2015 ICC Cricket World Cup?',
  //   correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  //   options: [
  //     'a) Chandika Hathurusingha',
  //     'b) Steve Rhodes',
  //     'c) Jamie Siddons',
  //     'd) Dave Whatmore'
  //   ],
  // ),
   Question(
    question:
        '12. In which year did Bangladesh win their first-ever ICC tournament, the ICC Trophy?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: ['a) 1995', 'b) 2000', 'c) 1997', 'd) 2003'],
  ),
  
 
  // Question(
  //   question: '13. What is the largest planet in our solar system?',
  //   correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  //   options: [
  //     'a) Earth',
  //     'b) Jupiter',
  //     'c) Saturn',
  //     'd) Venus',
  //   ],
  // ),
  // Question(
  //   question: '14. What is the longest river in the world?',
  //   correctAnswerIndex: 0,
  //   options: [
  //     'a) Nile',
  //     'b) Amazon',
  //     'c) Mississippi',
  //     'd) Danube',
  //   ],
  // ),
  // Question(
  //   question: '15. Who is the main character in the Harry Potter series?',
  //   correctAnswerIndex: 2,
  //   options: [
  //     'a) Hermione Granger',
  //     'b) Ron Weasley',
  //     'c) Harry Potter',
  //     'd) Neville Longbottom',
  //   ],
  // ),
  // Question(
  //   question: '16. What is the smallest planet in our solar system?',
  //   correctAnswerIndex: 3,
  //   options: [
  //     'a) Venus',
  //     'b) Mars',
  //     'c) Earth',
  //     'd) Mercury',
  //   ],
  // ),
  // Question(
  //   question: '17. Who wrote the play Romeo and Juliet?',
  //   correctAnswerIndex: 0,
  //   options: [
  //     'a) William Shakespeare',
  //     'b) Oscar Wilde',
  //     'c) Jane Austen',
  //     'd) Charles Dickens',
  //   ],
  // ),
  // Question(
  //   question: '18. What is the highest mountain in the world?',
  //   correctAnswerIndex: 1,
  //   options: [
  //     'a) Mont Blanc',
  //     'b) Everest',
  //     'c) Kilimanjaro',
  //     'd) Aconcagua',
  //   ],
  // ),
  // Question(
  //   question:
  //       '19. What is the name of the famous painting by Leonardo da Vinci that depicts a woman?',
  //   correctAnswerIndex: 3,
  //   options: [
  //     'a) Starry Night',
  //     'b) The Persistence of Memory',
  //     'c) The Last Supper',
  //     'd) Mona Lisa',
  //   ],
  // ),
  // Question(
  //   question:
  //       '20. Which bird, known for its vibrant colors, is the national bird of Bangladesh?',
  //   correctAnswerIndex: 3,
  //   options: [
  //     'a) Bald Eagle',
  //     'b) b) Peacock',
  //     'c) Sparrow',
  //     'd) Oriental Magpie-Robin (Doyel or Doel)',
  //   ],
  // ),
];
